Kate Culver

Kelowna, BC (250) 878-8360 kateeculver@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

I have 5 years of professional experience as a software engineer. I love thinking outside the box, problem solving, and puzzles. When it comes to my work, I'm highly engaged, eager to contribute, learn, and develop my skills further.

My colleagues have described me as a creative and personable individual who approaches tasks with passion and integrity, while maintaining a professional, realistic, and supportive demeanor.

EDUCATION

University of Victoria — Bachelor of Science

Sept 2013 - Aug 2017

Major in Mathematics, minor in Computer Science

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Pela — Software Engineer

Feb 2020 - Dec 2022, Kelowna BC

- Acted as lead developer on replatform from headless React to Shopify.
- ❖ Built features for headless GraphQL TypeScript React ecommerce sites.
- Contributed to Node.js AWS Lambdas.
- ❖ Improved SEO, GA tracking, and conversion optimization.
- Trained and mentored junior developers.

Cheeky Monkey Media — Intermediate Full Stack Developer

Oct 2019 - Feb 2020, Kelowna BC

- Improved internal React application and external React store locator.
- Improved and rebuilt PHP sites for agency clients.

ChatterBlock — Full Stack Software Developer

Sept 2017 - Aug 2019, Victoria BC

- Rebuilt customer user dashboard and business listing pages using PostgreSQL, Python, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS.
- ❖ Independently designed and built front-end web application user dashboard.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript

React

Python

Git

TypeScript

Node.js

GraphQL

Java

C

Jest

SQL

APPLICATIONS

GitHub/GitLab/Bitbucket

VS Code/JetBrains Suite

AWS

Dato CMS

Gatsby

Insomnia

Jira/Trello/Monday

Figma/Sketch

HOBBIES

Hiking, skiing, climbing, drawing/painting, meeting puppies.